Heading into twilight. Spreading out of wings tonight.
Got you jumping off the deck, shoveling the overdrive.
You take
a ride?
Morning, Scott.
Ghost Rider, this is strike. We have unknown aircraft.
Inbound Mustang. Your vector, zero 90 for bogey.
Who's up there? Cougar and Merlin and Maverick and Goose.
Great. Maverick and Goose.
Talk to me, Goose. Roger, I got him. Contact,
20 left at 30 miles. 900 knots closure. Cougar, you hear
that? Roger. Marlon, you got him?
Roger, I've got radar contact. I'll get a visual id.
Cougar, you hook him. Roger. And I'll clean him and fry him.
Mustang. Mustang, this is Ghost Rider,
203. I've got him inbound, bogey heading
270 at 10 miles. 900 knots closure.
Ghost Rider, take angels ten, left, 30.
Are we supposed to have visitors today? Negative, sir.
Call and see if he's a single. Roger.
Goose, you see a trailer? Negative, Merlin.
Looks like he's a single. Cougar, I'm gonna go head to head with him.
Take it easy, Maverick. I don't like this shit. I'm gonna brake high
and right and see if he's really alone.
We got a thousand knots closure, Mav. It's coming right at us.
Okay, buddy, what's on your mind?
Holy shit, there's two of them. Big 28s.
No one's been this close before. What the hell are they doing here? What's the
position? Uh, 250 miles out, sir. 250 miles?
Get em out of here.
Pookie, you've got MiG one. I'm going after MiG two.
I lost him in the sun.
Shit. What's he doing? You got him, murder.
He's coming around. He's coming around on our tail.
God damn it. This pokey's all over me.
What's the range now? 200 miles, sir.
They break 150 miles. Launch the alert five aircraft. Yes,
sir. Air speed,
300. Go get him, Mav. I'm going for missile lock.
See if we can scare this guy out of here. Come on,
lock up, baby. Lock up, baby.
Lock up. I got him locked. Bingo.
We got him, Mav. He's bugging out and going home. Mustang, this is
Maverick. Big two is headed home.
Alright, what's their position? 180 miles, bearing zero
10. Circuit.
Cougar, he's got missile lock on us. Get away from this guy. The hell is
this shit? He's engaging me.
God damn it. Mustang, this is Ghost Rider,
117. This bogey's all over me. He's got missile lock on me. Do I have
permission to fire? Do not fire until fired upon.
Goose, there they are, right below us. The mink's in
perfect firing position. He's right on Cougar's tail. No way, Goose. He'd have fired
by now. He's just trying to piss us off. Maverick, get down here and get
this asshole off me.
Easy, Cougar. Bring it back, hard right.
Help me engage. I'm on my
way.
I can't shoot this son of a bitch. Let's see if we can have a
little fun with him.
Is this your idea of fun, Mav?
Greetings.
Watch the birdie. Geez,
I cracked myself up.
This is a great shot, Mav. I should be a photographer.
Cougar, your tail is clear. Big one spooked out.
Cougar, this is Maverick. We've had
enough fun for one day, don't you think? I'm getting a little
low on fuel, so we're heading home.
See you on deck.
Cougar, we're running low on gas. We gotta get out of here.
Cougar,
we're on paper, Cougar. Let's do it.
Cougar. Come on, Cougar.
Sneaking back to the ship, man. Come on,
Cougar. Get him on deck as soon as possible. He's got to be low on
fuel. Cougar, we gotta land this
thing. We are way low on gas, you understand me?
You alright, man?
Maverick, you're at three quarters of a mile, call the ball.
Roger, Maverick has a ball. Cougar,
it's time to land. Goose, Cougar's in trouble. Come on,
mav, we're getting low on gas. Let's land this sucker.
Cougar.
God damn it, lyric, what are you doing, man? We've got no fuel for
this. We're going after Cougar. You tell him to
land that day. That's an order. Ghost rider,
you are instructed to land. Land immediately.
Any of you boys seen an aircraft carrier around here?
Man, if we got a little problem up here. That MiG really screwed him up.
I don't think he can make it back.
You're okay, Cougar. Just stand my wing,
I'll take you all the way in. Just stay with me.
Easy, Cougar. Just a walk in the park, buddy.
You below your little oak. Cougar.
Come on, buddy, pull up.
Pull up, Cougar. That's it.
Almost there.
For too little, Cougar. For too little, Cougar.
Give me some power. Some more power.
Power damage,
come in,
sir. Cougar, you should be in sickbay.
What's on your mind? My wife and kids, sir,
almost orphaned him today. I've never even seen him.
I don't know what happened up there, but I was so scared. Come on,
we've seen this before. No, sir.
I'm holding on too tight. I've lost the edge.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm sorry.
Cougar.
Thanks, Maverick.
Maverick, Goose, come in here. What the hell's going on?
I don't know. Shit.
Maverick, you just did an incredibly brave thing.
What you should have done was land your plane. You don't own that plane,
the taxpayers do. Son, your ego is writing checks
your body can't cash. You've been busted.
You lost your qualifications as section leader three times.
Put and hacked twice. By me. With a history of
high speed passes over five air controlled towers and
one admiral's daughter. Penny Benjamin.
And you, asshole, you're lucky to be here. Thank you,
sir. And let's not bullshit, Maverick. Your family name ain't
the best in the Navy. You need to be doing it better and cleaner
than the other guy. Now, what is it with you? Just want to serve
my country, be the best fighter pilot in the Navy, sir. Don't scream screw around
with me, Maverick. You're a hell of an instinctive pilot.
Maybe too good. I'd like to bust your butt, but I can't.
I got another problem here. I gotta send somebody from
this squadron to Miramar. I gotta do something
here. I still can't believe it. I gotta give you your
dream shot. I'm gonna send you up against the best. You two characters
are going to top gun. For five
weeks, you're gonna fly against the best fighter pilots in the world. You were
number two. Cougar was number one. Cougar lost and turned in his wings.
You guys are number one. But you
remember one thing. You screw up just this much.
You'll be flying a cargo plane full of rubber dog shit out of Hong
Kong. Yes, sir.
That is all. Tell me about the mix some other time.
Gentlemen. Good luck, gentlemen.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
During Korea and the Navy kill ratio was twelve to one.
We shot down twelve of their jets for every one of ours. During Vietnam,
that ratio fell to three to one. Our pilots become dependent upon missiles.
They had lost some of their dogfighting skills. Now,
top gun was created to teach Acm. Air combat maneuvering.
Dogfighting. This gives me a hard eye. By the end
of Vietnam, that ratio was back up to twelve to one. Don't tease me lines,
please. I'd like to take this opportunity to introduce you to
our commanding officer at Top Gun. Very first man to win the Top gun trophy.
You will not find a finer fighter pilot anywhere in the world.
Commander Mike Metcalf. Call sign, Viper.
Gentlemen, you are the top 1%
of all naval aviators.
The elite. Best of the best.
We'll make it better. Fly at least
two combat missions a day, ten classes in between,
and evaluations of your performance. Now, in each combat
sequence, you're going to meet a different challenge. Every encounter
is going to be much more difficult. We're going to teach you to fly the
f 14 right to the edge of the envelope, faster than you've ever flown before.
More dangerous. We don't make policy
here, gentlemen. Elected officials,
civilians, do that. We are the instruments of that policy.
And although we're not at war, we must always act
as though we are at war. What are you doing? Tip of the spear.
Just wondering. Best be sure who's the best. In case some of
you wonder who the best is, they're up here on this plaque
on the wall. The best driver in his Rio from each class has his name
on it, and they
have the option to come back here to be top gun instructors.
You think your name is going to be on that plaque?
Yes, sir. That's pretty arrogant,
considering the company you're in.
Yes, sir. I like that in the
pilot. Just remember, when it's over out
there, we're all on the same team.
Gentlemen, this school is about combat. There are no
points for second place.
Dismissed. He's going.
The plaque for the alternates is down in the ladies room.
Oh, Jesus. Oh, you kill me. You really do.
No, no, no. There's two o's in Goose, boys.
This is what I call a target rich environment. You live your
life between your legs. Matt, go see if you can get laid in a place
like this. I'm telling you, I'd be happy to find a girl who talked
dirty to me.
Matt, you want to know who the best is?
That's him. Iceman. That's the way he flies.
Ice cold. No mistakes. Just wears you down. You get
bored, frustrated, do something stupid, and he's got you.
Hey. Hey, slider. Thought you wanted to be a pilot, man.
What happened? Goose, you're such a dickhead. Whose butt did you kiss
to get in here, huh? Well, the list is long but distinguished. Yeah, well,
so is my Johnson. So you're flying with Iceman,
huh? Mister Iceman to you. Hey, mother Goose, how's it going? I'm doing good.
Tom, this is Pete Mitchell. Tom Kazanski.
Congratulations on Top Gun. Thank you. Sorry to hear about Cougar.
He and I were like brothers. In flight school. He was a good man.
Still is a good man. Yeah, that's what I meant. Thought so.
Say, you need any help?
With what? You figured it out yet?
What's that? Who's the best pilot?
No, I think I can figure that one out on my own. I heard
that about you. You like to work alone,
mav? You must have sold under a lucky star, huh? I mean, first the MiG,
and then you guys slide into cougar spot. We didn't slide into cougar spot.
It was ours, okay? Yeah, well, some pilots wait their whole career just to see
him make up close. Guess you guys are lucky and famous,
huh? No, you mean notorious.
I'll see you later. You can count on it.
They were abused children. We're gonna
have a good time. Time? Always.
Okay, I guess it's my turn, isn't it? All right,
the bet is $20. $20? You have to have carnal
knowledge, of a lady this time,
on the premises. On the premises.
Come on, mav, that's a bet. I don't know.
It just doesn't seem fair. For you, I mean.
But, uh. She's lost that loving
feeling. She's like. No, she hasn't. Yes, she has. She has not
lost that love. Cause she's lost it. Matt. Come on.
I hate it when she does that.
Excuse me, miss. Hey, hey. Don't worry. I'll take care of this.
You never close your. Your eyes anymore.
When I kiss your lips.
There's no tenderness like before
in your fingertips.
You're trying hard not to show it,
baby. But, baby,
believe me, I know I did.
You've lost.
You lost that love and feeling.
Now it's gone, gone,
gone. Whoa, whoa.
Sit down. I do.
Save it, baby. I'll give down all my knees
for you. I love
that song. I've never seen that approach.
How long have you two been doing this act? Oh, I don't know. Since puberty?
Right. Puberty. I'm Charlotte Blackwood.
I'm Maverick. Maverick. Does your
mother not like you or something? No, it's my call sign.
Pilot. That's right. A naval aviator.
No, actually, you've only done this twice. Oh,
how'd you do? Crashed and burned on
the first one. It wasn't pretty. Second?
I don't know. I'll tell you tomorrow. But it's looking good so far.
Well, Maverick. Look, my friend's just
arrived, so it's been great talking to you. Perry.
Hi. Hi. Here you go. Oh, I'll be with you in just a second.
Listen, can I ask you a personal question?
That depends. Are you
a good pilot? I can
hold my own. Great.
Then I won't have to worry about you making your living as a singer.
I'm gonna need a beer to put these flames out, yo.
It's great, mav. Real slick.
It's a long cruise, was it, sailor? It's too long.
What'd you want to do, just drop right down on the tile and go for
it? I had this
counter in mind. That would be very,
very comfortable. Yeah, it could be.
Actually, I came in here to save you from making a
big mistake with that older guy. Really?
So I could go onto a bigger one with a young guy like yourself?
Maybe. No. I've got to
be at work very early in the morning. What are you doing here?
Your friend was magnificent.
No.
Now, you'll also be trained and evaluated by a few civilian specialists.
Civilians are here because they are our very best source of information on enemy aircraft.
One of the most qualified is our tag rep, callsign Charlie.
She has a PhD in astrophysics, and she's also a civilian
contractor. So you do not salute her. But you better listen to her,
because the Pentagon listens to her about your proficiency. It's all yours, Charlie.
Thank you. Hello.
We will be dealing with f five s and a four s as our
mixed simulators. Now then, as most of you know,
the f five doesn't have the thrust to weight ratio that
the MiG 28 has. And it doesn't bleed energy
below 300 knots like the MiG 28.
However, the MiG 28 does have a
problem with its inverted flight tanks. It won't do a
negative g pushover. The latest intelligence tells
us that the most it will do is one negative.
Excuse me, lieutenant. Is there something wrong?
Yes, ma'am. The data on the MiG is inaccurate.
How's that, lieutenant? Well, I just happened
to see a MiG 28. We do. We? Sorry,
goose. We happen to see a MiG 28
do a 4G negative dive. Where did
you see this? That's classified.
It's what? It's classified.
I could tell you, but then I'd have to kill you. Lieutenant, I have top
secret clearance. The Pentagon sees to it that I know more than
you. Well, ma'am, it doesn't seem so
in this case, now, does it? So,
lieutenant, where exactly were
you? Well, we. Thank you
started up on his when he pulled through the clouds, and then I moved
in above him. Well, if you were directly above him, how could you
see him? Because I was inverted.
No, he was. Man, it was a really great move. She was inverted.
You were in a 4G inverted dive with
a MiG 28? Yes, ma'am.
At what range? No, about 2 meters.
Well, it's actually about one and a half. I think it was one and a
half. I've got a great Polaroid of it. And he's right. There must be one
and a half. Was a nice picture. He wasn't half a picture. Lieutenant,
what were you doing there?
Communicating. Communicating. Keeping up foreign
relations. I was, you know, giving him the bird.
You know, the finger? Yes, I know the finger, Goose.
I'm sorry. I hate it when.
Excuse me. So you're the one.
Yes, ma'am. All right, gentlemen,
we have a hop to take. The hard deck on this hop will be 10,000ft.
There'll be no engagement below that. Move it,
lieutenant.
Okay. Well, don't be late again. You look great, honey. Thanks,
dear. See you in pre flight. Lieutenant.
Why didn't you tell me that you were a famous Miggin sultan? Would it
made any difference? Not in the ladies room, no. What would have?
I'm an instructor at this school. I see 20 new hot shots every
eight weeks. Now, I'm sure you can figure that out.
Look, lieutenant, I'd just really like to hear
about the nibs sometime. We've got security clearance.
You can read about it.
Maverick. I'm curious.
Who was covering cougar
while you were showboating with this migration?
Cougar was doing just fine. Uh huh.
Gentlemen, this is your first hop. The jets you are flying against are
smaller, faster and more maneuverable. Just like the enemy migs.
The clock is ticking, and as of now, we are keeping score.
I lost him, Goose.
Show me what you got, kid. I lost him.
I'm looking, I'm looking.
I got him. I got him. He's on our tail, coming hard. Yeah, I got
him. I got him. Here we go.
All right. Talk to me, Goose. He's still back there. He's closing in on us.
He's closing fast. You can run, kid, but you can't hide.
Jester. Let's see if I can give you a run for your money here.
Watch your mountains.
I still got him. He's still back there. Come on, mav. Do some
of that pilot shit. Yeah, I got him.
Come on, bring it. Right, dudes. I've had about
enough of this shit. When you
hit the brakes, I'll fly right by. Okay, you're mine.
Whoo.
Jesus Christ.
Let's see what you got now, Chester. Okay, man, let's turn
and burn.
He's going vertical. So am I. We're going ballistic, man.
Go get him.
He's going for the hard deck. Let's get down there first and nail him,
Mav. No way, Jester. You're mine.
I got you now.
Jester's dead. Jester's dead.
Yee haw. Get your
butts above the hard deck and return to pace immediately.
Yes, sir.
Tower, this is Ghost Rider requesting a flyby.
Negative, Ghost Rider. The pattern is full. No, no, mav,
this is not a good idea. Sorry, Goose, but it's
time to buzz the tower.
Goddamn son of a bitch.
They pulled the fire.
Yee ha. Jester's dead. One pissed.
Bullshit. Didn't everybody? Hell, no, man. We got our butts kicked.
30 seconds. We went like this, he went like that. I said
to Hollywood, where'd he go? Hollywood said, when? Who go?
Yeah, and he's laughing at us. Right on the radio, he's laughing at us.
No, it's me laughing, dickhead. We won. All right,
they won two, man. That's not what I heard. No, we did.
We got gesture. No, no, below the hard deck
does not count. Hard deck, my ass. We nailed that sentiment.
You guys really are cowboys. What's your problem,
Kazansky? You're everyone's
problem. That's because every time you go up in the air, you're unsafe.
I don't like you because you're dangerous. That's right,
ice man. I am
dangerous.
Maverick, you and Goose get your butts out of that flight.
Gearing up the viper's office now.
Remember, boys, no points for second place.
You're a lot brighter than you look. Oh, you shut up. Okay, don't worry.
Okay, I will. Don't worry. Two of your snot nose jockeys at a
flyby on my tower and over 400 nuts.
I want somebody's butt. I want it now. I'm at it.
Oh, God damn it, Hatch. Twice.
I want some butts.
Well, I don't. Just about COVID the flat buys.
Follow me,
gentlemen. You had
a hell of a first day.
The hard deck for this hop was 10,000ft. You knew
it, you broke it. You followed Commander Heatherly below
after he lost sight of you and called no joy.
Why? Sir, I had
Commander Heatherly in my sights. He saw me
move in for the kill. He then proceeded below the hard deck.
We weren't below 10,000 for more than a few seconds.
I had the shot, there was no danger, so I took it.
You took it and broke a major rule of engagement.
Then you broke another one with that circus stunt flyby,
Lieutenant Mitchell. Top gun rules of engagement exist
for your safety and for that of your team. They are not flexible, nor am
I. Either obey them or you are history. Is that
clear? Yes,
sir.
Dismissed.
Really enjoyed that map. Thanks a lot. Holy shit.
Maybe I could learn how to be a truck driver. Mav, you have the number
of that truck driving school we saw on tv? Truck master, I think it is.
I might need that spit nurse.
Report says it all. He's a wild card.
Flies by the seat of his pants. Completely unpredictable.
He got you, didn't he?
Yeah. Maverick flew
with his old man.
Tell me one thing. You had to go into battle.
Would you want him with you? I don't know.
Just don't know.
Still awake? Yeah.
What's up? Can't sleep.
You know, when I first realized that going to top gun, all I could think
about was getting that trophy.
I gotta be straight with you. Math right
now. I just hope we graduate.
I got a family to think about. I can't afford to blow this.
I guess I fly. My. Wasn't such a big hit, huh?
Look, man, I know it's tough for you. It wouldn't let you in
the academy. Cause you're Duke Mitchell's kid.
You have to live with that reputation. It's like every
time we go up there, it's like you're flying against a ghost.
Makes me nervous.
You're the only family I've got. I'm not gonna
let you down. I promise you.
Get out of here.
A rolling reversal would work well in that situation.
If I reversed on a hard cross, I could immediately go to guns on him.
Yeah, but at this speed, it's too fast.
It's a little bit too aggressive.
Too aggressive?
Yeah. I guess when I see something, I go right after it.
You didn't tell me who you were the other night. You didn't give me a
chance, did you? You deserved it.
I know. But you
were tempted to ask me out for dinner.
No. No. I don't
date students.
I can see it's dangerous for you. But if the government trusts
me, maybe you could.
It takes a lot more than just fancy flying.
Crashed and burn, huh, mav?
Slider.
You stink.
Let's go. Okay. I step was a
ride.
That's good. Come on. Come on.
Come on now. Four to seven. Now. We can get them.
Guys are animals.
Okay. Yeah. Stay down.
Come on. We won. We won.
Just one more game. That evens it up. Come on, we can take it.
No, we can't. We got it. I got some things I gotta take care of.
Take care of. Just one more game. Please. For me?
Sorry. You're sorry? Come on. For me,
damn it.
What, no singing?
Look, I'm. No apologies.
If you don't mind, I'm gonna just take a quick shower while you're finishing
up here.
Yeah, I do mind. I'm hungry.
And then I thought about it.
I thought, you know, Charlie,
he's a smart guy. Why don't you just tell him why you've
got him in? Well,
it's the MiG.
The MiG. You were the only pilot who's been up
against a MiG 28.
I'm trying for this big promotion at work, and if I get it, I'm not
gonna be here much longer. Seems to
me you've got it all figured out.
Mm. Except you didn't
forget the wine.
Sorry. You always get
what you want? No, not always.
Yeah, maybe relax about the. Make this
music our
friend.
My folks loved it. Never heard this in years.
My mother used to call down from her room and have
me play this over and over again. I got so sick
of it. Not her.
She just sit up there alone, just listening.
Hours.
She died shortly after him.
What happened to your father?
I guess I kind of figured with your security clearance,
you'd know more about him than I do.
Get that far?
Well, that's a big mystery.
He disappeared in f 4, November 5,
1965.
The stink of it was. He screwed up.
No way. My old man was a great
fighter.
But who the hell knows? It's all classified.
Somebody must know.
Is that why you're always second best up there?
You are direct, aren't you?
Sorry I was late.
I'm sorry for being direct. No apologies.
This is gonna be complicated.
Where are you going?
Gonna take a shower.
Thank you. Enjoy being here.
It looks like you need another shower.
Right.
I'm gonna be honest with you.
Your MiG sighting is really important to my work, but,
um,
I don't normally invite students to my house.
You're, uh.
But please understand, I still have a job to do,
sir.
I'm glad we got that straight.
I told her how tough it is here, you know, my ass dragging like an
old, tired dog. I told her that you didn't even have a woman here.
I really. You know what she said? Well, he probably doesn't
have one. He's got eight.
So, Maverick. Goose tells me you're in love with one of your instructors.
Is that right? I didn't tell her that.
She did. I can't. There was a secret.
The bogey has good position right here. All right, freeze frame.
Moment of choice. DF 14 is defensive. He has
a chance to bug out right here. Better to retire and
save your aircraft. And push a bad position.
Johnny, jump in here anytime now. You stay in that diamond
another 3 seconds, the bogey's gonna blow you out of the sky.
You take a hard right, select zone five.
You can extend and escape.
You made a bad choice.
Johnny.
Aircraft one performs a split s?
That's the last thing you should do. The MiG's right on your tail.
Tree's there. Please. The MiG has you
in his gun site. What were you thinking at this point? You don't have
time to think up there. If you think, you're dead.
That's a big gamble with a $30 million plane,
lieutenant.
Unfortunately, the gamble worked. The MiG never got a clean shot.
Maverick makes an aggressive vertical move here, comes over the
top. And he defeats the bandit with a missile shot.
The encounter was a victory, but I think that we've shown
it as an example of what not to do.
Next. Gutsiest move I ever saw,
man.
Now then, this is a perfect example of a textbook maneuver.
Lieutenant.
Lieutenant. My review of your flight performance and
the task was right on, in my professional opinion. I can't
hear you.
Jesus Christ. And you think I'm reckless? When I fly,
I'll have you know that my crew and my plane come first. Well, I'm going
to finish my sentence, lieutenant. My review of your flight performance
was right on. Is that right? That is right. But I
held something back. I see some real genius in your flying,
Maverick, but I can't say that in there. I was afraid that everyone in that
tax trailer would see right through me. And I just don't want anyone to
know that I've fallen for him.
Watching in slow motion as you turn
back take
my breath away,
my love take my breath away,
my love turn my breath
away hey,
Mavericks. Yeah? Hear about ice?
What's that? You want another one? Really?
Yeah. I feel the need.
The need for speed.
Gentlemen, this is top 19. Multiple aircraft,
multiple bogeys. Your training is half over. The competition for
the top gun trophy remains tight. First place,
Iceman. Second place, Maverick. Just two points behind.
Here they are. 3 miles left, 10:00. I don't think they see
us yet. Okay, I see two. A four is left, 10:00 level.
Continue left turn.
Good morning, gentlemen. The temperature is 110 degrees.
Holy shit, it's Viper. Viper's up here?
Great. Oh, shit. Great.
He's probably saying, holy shit, it's Maverick and Goose. Yeah, I'm sure he's
saying that. That I've
got my eye in the northern bogey. Roger. I got the southern guy.
Hollywood, you've got the lead. I'll cover you.
Break now, Chester.
Hollywood, we're losing piper. Let's just stay on jester. Roger, I'm on him.
Goose, find Viper. He's out there somewhere. Stay with
Hollywood, Mav. We're covering his wing.
Goose, there's Viper. 03:00 low. Stay with Hollywood,
Mav. Where is cover? Don't kill. You leave me, Maverick.
Hollywood, you're looking good. I'm going after Viper.
God damn you, Maverick. Mav, don't leave him.
Goose, Hollywood's okay. I want Viper.
Standby. Viper's coming down.
Holy shit, we're head to head. I can't believe we're doing
this.
Rock and roll. Here's our chance. It's a big one, Goose.
Come on. God damn it.
Come on, man, keep coming.
Okay, sidewinder missile selected. Come on, baby. Come on,
baby. Come around, come around. That's it, that's it.
Jesus, the sky's coming, coach. Where's he going?
Come on, come on, come on. Keep coming, keep coming.
Come on, Danny.
Damn, this gets good. Still close for
missiles, Goose. I'm switching to guns.
Come on, come on, come on.
Stick with it, stick with it.
Hold it. Goose, check our tail. Shit, there's Chester.
Bingo, Maverick's dead. You're out of there, kid.
Defense Department regrets to inform you that your sons are dead because they
were stupid. Great balls of
fire. Okay, knock it out, gentlemen.
Let's go home. Fight for as the lead.
30 seconds, Wolfman. I'm coming in.
Shut up. God. Fuck knows. That was some
of the best flying I've seen yet. Right up to the part where you got
killed. You never, never leave your wingman.
Maverick, it's not your flying,
it's your attitude. The enemy's dangerous,
but right now, you're worse than the enemy. You're dangerous
and foolish. You may not like the guys flying with you,
they may not like you, but whose side are you on?
Well, at least Viper got Iceman before he got us.
He still got a shot at it. That was stupid.
I know better than that. It'll never
happen again.
I know,
I know.
You shake my nerves and you rattle my brain. Think about
your love. Drives a man insane. You break my way.
Oh, what a thrill. Goodness gracious, great balls
of fire. Woo. Maverick, would you go fetch him?
Doesn't he ever embarrass you? Goose? Hell, no.
Well, it was the admiral's daughter.
What? He told
me all about the time you went ballistic with Penny Benjamin.
Did he well, that's great. He tells me about all of them
ever. Uh huh. How my little angel goose goes home early
for church. And you, you always go home with
the hot women. All right. Thank you, Carol. I'm gonna go embarrass
myself with Goose for a while.
You shake my nerves and you out on my brain. Think back your love.
Guys, a man is saying you broke my will.
Goodness, gracious, great balls of fire.
I would love to be able to warn you off about Maverick, but I
just love him to death.
You know, I've known Pete for a lot of years now, and I'm
telling you one thing's for certain. There are hearts breaking wide
open all over the world tonight. Why?
Because unless you are a fool, a boy is off the market.
He is 100% prime time in
love with you. Hey,
Goose, you big dad. That's me, honey. Take me
to bed or lose me forever. Show me the way home, honey.
Come on, Brad, let's sing with the family.
Awesome. You shake my nerves and you rattle my brave.
We better love. Got the man. You both
are willing?
Goodness gracious, great balls of fire. Woo hoo.
Ow.
Maverick,
you big stud. Take me to bed or lose me forever.
Okay, gentlemen, this is hop 31. Two weeks to graduation.
Top gun trophy still up for grabs, so every point counts.
Never under tension. Big and unit taxing,
riding through the danger
zone.
Well, it's bottom of the 9th, the score is tied. It's time for the big
one. You up for this one, Maverick? Just a walk in the parking,
Kazansky.
Contact. Multiple bogeys. One six, five,
2 miles. Looks like they're going away from us. Oh, I see them.
Tally ho. Right, 02:00. I'm in. I'm in.
That son of a bitch cut me off.
Come on, come on. Jesus Christ. Ice, take the
shot. Come on, ice, get the hell out of there. I can't get
the angle. I'm too close for missiles. I'm switching to guns.
Ice, fire or clear.
Look at this. Jesus Christ, I can take a shot right here. I need
another 20 seconds, then I've got him.
I'm moving in. I've got the shot. Come on, Mav, let's get in there.
Come on, Mav. Maverick's getting impatient. Ice, come on,
take the shot. Ten more seconds, then I've got him.
Come on, ice, get the hell out of there. Let's do it, Mav.
Ice, come off high right. I'm in. Five more seconds. Come off
high right, Ice. I'm in. I'm off. Shit.
We're in. His jet wash. Oh. Oh, shit.
This is not good. Shit. We got a flame out, Mav.
Engine one is out. Engine two is out.
Bruce. I'm losing control. I'm losing control. I can't. I can't control it. It won't
recover. Shit.
Couple it up, Mav, we're out of control. This is not good.
This is not good. Mayday, mayday. Mav's in trouble. He's in a flat spin.
He's heading out to C.
Altitude 8000,
7006 words. Six fam.
I'm head forward, Goose. I can't reach the ejection handle.
Goose, you're gonna have to punch this out. I can't reach the ejection
handle. Eject,
eject, eject. Watch the canopy.
Go. Go. Oh, no.
Oh, God. Oh, God. Oh, God.
Sir, let go of him. You gotta let him go,
sir.
How you doing? I'm all right.
Ghost is dead. I know ply
Jet's long enough. Something like this happens.
Here's my real. My responsibility.
My squad. In Vietnam, we lost eight of 18 aircraft. Ten men.
First one dies, you die too. But there
will be others. You can count
on it. You gotta let him
go.
You gotta let him go.
I think maybe it was my fault.
I don't know what the hell went wrong.
I'd like to help. I know it's difficult.
God, I want him back.
I'll be here if you need me, okay?
God, he loves flying with you, Maverick.
He'd have flown anyway. Without you.
He'd have hated it, but he would have done it.
We find that the f 14 flat spin was induced
by the disruption of airflow into the starboard engine.
This disruption stalled the engine,
which produced enough yaw rake to. To induce
a spin which was unrecoverable.
There was no way Lieutenant Mitchell could either see or avoid the jet wash which
produced the engine stall. Therefore, the board of inquiry finds
that Lieutenant Pete Mitchell was not at fault in the accident of the 29 July.
Lieutenant Mitchell's record will be cleared of this incident. Lieutenant Mitchell
is restored to flight status without further delay.
These proceedings are closed.
Get him up flying, soon.
Come on, kid. Come on. Get in there. Engage. All right, you got a bogey
at 02:00 low, Maverick. You got the angle. Piece of cake, pal.
Take the shot. Just take the shot.
Time, Maverick.
Hey, where the hell are you going? Uh, it's not good. It. It doesn't look
good. What do you mean, it doesn't look good? It doesn't get to look any
better than that.
Hey, man, we could have had it. Hey, we could have
had it, man. I will fire when I
am goddamn good and ready. You got that?
You can't get back in the saddle. Won't engage. It's only
been a few days. You know, he just might not make it back.
Keep sending him up.
Mitchell. I'm sorry about
Goose.
Everybody liked him.
I'm sorry.
Hi, it's Wolfman now.
Maverick just quit.
Excuse me.
May I? Please.
Um. I'll. I'll have what he's having.
Hemlock isn't. Nice one.
You weren't gonna say goodbye?
I heard you got that job in Washington.
Congratulations. Thanks.
But I wasn't gonna leave without saying goodbye.
It's good to see you. Thanks.
Where you going? You don't even
have a ticket, do you? Listen,
I've seen all the evidence, and it's not your responsibility.
It's not your fault.
You're one of the best. Best pilots in the Navy.
What you do up there, it's dangerous.
But you've got to go on. How?
You don't understand. When I first met
you, you were larger than life.
Look at you.
You're not going to be unless you're going mach two with
your hair on fire. You know that. No, it's over.
It's just over. To be the best of the best means
you make mistakes and then you go on. It's just
like the rest of us. You don't think I know that?
I'm here to help.
Okay. Thank you.
If I wanted help, really, I would have asked for it.
That's why I'm too late.
You've already left.
You didn't learn a damn thing, did you?
Except to quit.
You've got that maneuver down real well.
So long, Pete Mitchell.
Well, hi, Maverick. Come on in. How are you doing?
Good. You sure? You feeling okay? Great.
Jamie, come on. Can I get you a drink or. No, thank you.
Okay, well, why don't you just. Thank you very much. Make you so comfortable because
Mike will be right down. Okay. Thank you.
I flew with the old man. Year 51. They risk any?
You're a lot like he was. Only better and
worse. He was a natural
heroic son of a bitch, that one.
So we did do it, Mike.
Yeah, you did it right.
Is that why you fly the way you do? Trying to prove something?
Yeah, your old man did it right.
What I'm about to tell you, it's classified. Could end my career.
We were in the worst dogfight I ever dreamed of.
There were bogies, like fireflies all over the sky.
His f four was hit. He was wounded, but he could have made it back.
He stayed in it. Saved three planes before he bought it.
How come I never heard that before? Well, that's not something the State Department tells
dependents when the battle occurred over the wrong line. Some map.
So you were there. I was there.
It's on your mind.
My options, sir?
Simple. First,
you've required enough points to show up tomorrow and graduate with your top gun class.
Or you can quit.
There'd be no discourse. Grace, that spin was hell. It would have shook me
up. So you think I should quit? I didn't
say that. The simple fact
is you feel responsible for Goose and you have a confidence problem.
Now, I'm not going to sit here and blow sunshine up your ass, lieutenant.
A good pilot is compelled to always evaluate what's
happened so he can apply what he's learned.
Up there, we gotta push it.
That's our job.
It's your option, lieutenant. All yours.
Sorry to bother you on a Sunday, sir, but thank you very much for
your time. No problem. Good luck.
Challenged you to fly against the.
You know what he's planning to do.
Gotta be hard on that guy, though, you know?
Congratulations. Thank you.
Congratulations. Thanks, Pat.
Gentlemen, I hate to break up the party before it
really gets out of hand. There is work to be done. Some of you have
to depart immediately. We have a crisis situation.
Ice, slider, yoke. Hollywood,
Wolfman.
Maverick. Sir.
Maverick, you'll get to rear when you get to your ship.
And if you don't, give me a call.
I'll fly with you,
sir.
Gentlemen, this is bullseye. The communication ship SS
Layton has become disabled and has wandered into foreign territory.
A rescue operation is to begin within the hour. Your mission is
to give air support to that rescue. There are
migs in the area and tensions are high. If you witness a hostile act,
you will return fire. Those migs carry the
Exocet anti ship missile. They can fire that missile from 100 miles
away. Gentlemen, this is the real thing.
This is what you've been trained for. You are America's best.
Make us proud, ice. Yes, sir.
Hollywood. Yes. Sector two. Maverick, you back him up
with Merlin on ready five. Yes,
sir.
Rise. Excuse me, sir.
Yes? This is not personal, but with regard
to Maverick, is he the best? I know it's on
your mind, Kazanski. Just get on it.
You'll see this tiger Mustang. We get the chance to give me a mode
four check. Voodoo one, you've got a pair of bogeys,
12:00, 15 miles. Voodoo one, voodoo 1090,
radar contact 15 miles. They're doing 500 knots.
Roger, that's your bogey.
Come, dinner. Head 15 miles. Airspeed is 600 knots.
Focus jet, 650, roll. Close together. Let's take a wider split.
They're 15,000ft now. Dead ahead, 10 miles. Airspeed is
still increasing. 800 knots. Dead ahead now,
8 miles. Dead ahead, now, 8 miles. Wood, you got them?
Not yet. I can't see them. They must be close. I'm getting a hard on.
Okay, Wood, I'm taking the lead. Let's identify him. Roger, Ice,
you got the lead. I'm on your left side, a little low.
Maverick's up and ready. And alert five's good. Good.
Still maneuvering, zero 90.
Okay, Wood, let's bring it to the right and we'll get a better angle on
him.
Ice, we got a problem here. Now, I'm breaking up four aircraft on the radar.
Not one pair, two pair. Repeat, four bogeys. Wood, we've got
four bogeys.
Wrong, make that five. There's five, sir. It's five?
Yes, sir.
Oh, shit. He's got a radar lock on us.
Get out of there, Hollywood. Get out of there, God damn it.
My glyph. I'm hit. I'm hit. We're coming apart.
I can't control it. Oh. 90 for 20. We're good.
What's been hit? What's been hit? Shit. What's been hit? Fudu one, Fudu one,
what's been hit? What's been hit? We've lost Hollywood. Repeat, we've lost Hollywood.
Launch maverick on alert five.
Mavericks airborne. Iceman, what's your position? Zero 90 at
180 miles. Coming in left three.
MiG state ahead. Coming down the left side.
I'm going after him. I'm bringing around to the left.
We got four on our tail. That made six of them lead. Make us
closer than the guns. Range firing.
Break right. Mustang,
this is Voodoo one. We are totally defensive. Launch the alert fighters. Where? Where are
they? 160 miles and closing in fast, sir. Ready Willet and Simkinov
cats three and four.
Maverick, supersonic. I'll be there in 30 seconds. Move your ass. Get up here.
I'm engaged with five. Repeat, five. I'm in deep shit.
What about Willard and Simpkin? Both catapults are broken. We can't
launch any aircraft yet, sir. How long? It'll take ten minutes.
Bullshit. Ten minutes. This thing will be over in two minutes. Get on it.
One big 12:00 high. Wanna make 12:00 high? Watch you
back. Watch you back.
Right, right.
Shit, that was close. Maverick, how about the belt down here. Where the hell are
you? Gun. Come on, kid, hang in there.
Jesus Christ.
Maverick, how about some help? Engage. God damn it.
Maverick, we got a MiG on our tail.
Watch out. Watch out.
Shit, we just flew right through his jet wash.
Get control, Mav. Get control.
Good recovery, man. Okay, let's. Let's get in there.
Come on, we gotta help ice. Come on, let's get back and
engage, Maverick, come on. It's no good. Get in there, Maverick.
It's no good.
God damn it. Maverick's disengaging. I knew it.
Shit. God damn it, Maverick.
Get in there, Maverick. You can't leave him. Come on, Maverick. What the
hell are you doing, Maverick, get in there, for Christ's sake. Lice is
in trouble. He's got no cover. Get in there, Maverick. You won't last down there
alone. Get in the fight, for Christ's sake. Maverick.
Maverick.
Maverick's re engaging, sir.
I can't get him off my tail. Ice, I've got your big dead ahead.
I've got him dead ahead. Good toad.
I got good toad. I got toned. I got toned. Fire it.
Where? Where are they? 155 miles. Two big stead ahead.
Closure 800 miles an hour. I see him. I see him. I'm gonna take him
down the left side. Oh,
my God.
Ice is right below us. He's got a MiG on his tail.
He's firing. Brake. Laugh. Brake lamp here.
Our shot here. I'm coming in,
Ice, I'm coming in.
Got two migs dead ahead. I got him,
Mav. One MiG passing between us.
You gotta make on your left. On your left. 03:00 he's gonna fire. He's gonna
fire.
Favor, get the guys to the north. Check the guys to the north.
Banking left. Banking left.
There he is. Get a mic. Get him. Okay, you guys, I'm coming
in.
Maverick, got a mink coming around on our tail. We gotta get out of here.
I can't leave Ice. He's still coming around. He's still coming around. He's gonna get
behind us. I'm not leaving my wing band.
I'm on his tail. I'm on his tail. I'm going for it. I'm going for
it. I'm going for the shot right now. Roger, engage.
I've got ready to unlock. Good tone. I'm taking a shot.
Fire.
Bingo. Watch that sucker. Yeah. Ice, watch out, there's a
mid to your right. He's firing.
I'm hit. I'm hit.
We're hit. We're hitting the right engine. I'm shutting it down. I'm shutting it down.
Keep watching. Keep watching.
Coming in, ice. Coming in,
ice. That bogey's still behind you. I'm maneuvering for a shot. Stay with
him, Matt. Stay with him. Take the shot. Nail him. Nail him. Shit.
Ice, I can't get a tone. Shoot, Maverick. I can't get him off my tail.
Maverick. We're hit. We're hit again. It's okay. All systems are functioning.
We're okay. Ice, on the count of three, brake hard right.
Three, two, one.
Brake right.
Firing.
Damn it. Fished, don't let him go. Keep on him,
Mav. Keep on him. I got him. I got him.
Here comes a shotty backstreet
move. There's a MiG undertale. There's a MiG undertale. We've got a problem here.
We've only got one missile left. Approaching 110 miles, sir.
God damn him. I got him. I got him. He's right on us. He's between
our tails.
Shit.
You haven't lost him. He's still with us.
What are you doing? You're slowing down. You're slowing down. I'm bringing him in closer,
Merlin. You're gonna do what?
This is it, Maverick. I'm gonna hit the brakes. He'll fly right by. Shit,
he's gonna get a lock on us.
I got it. Good luck. Firing.
Whoo. Splash. Four.
Mustang, this scoodoo. Three remaining migs are bugging
out.
Mustang, this is Maverick, requesting flyby.
Negative, ghost rider. The pattern is fault.
Excuse me. Something I should know about?
You are still dangerous. Dangerous?
You can be my wingman anytime.
Bullshit. You can be mine.
Maverick. Sir? How's it feel to be on the front page? Every newspaper
in the english speaking world? Even though the other side denies the incident.
Congratulations. Thank you, sir. They gave you your choice of duty, son.
Anything, anywhere. Do you believe that shit? Where do you think you want to go?
I thought of being an instructor, sir.
Top Gun? Yes, sir.
God help us.
You never close your eyes anymore.
When I kiss your lips.
There's no tenderness. Like grief.
Holding your finger. Tears.
You're trying hard not to show it.
But, baby,
baby, I must.
You lost. I love you.
Go keep it.
I heard the best of the best. We're gonna be back here, so.
Baby, baby, I'd get down.
All this could be complicated,
you know, in the first one, they crashed and
burned. And the second?
Don't find every day good so far.
So don't, don't,
don't, don't let us live away baby,
baby, I made you peace.
I need your love. Did I know I need?
Bring it on my, bring it on my head?
Bring back that love?
Heroes around the sun? Doesn't mean
that much to me?
Higher and higher in my soul?
There's a raging fire in
the sky tonight?
I wanna ride on the silver dome? Far into
the night? Can I make you take
me out?
Me? I?
Take me on your way?
Just a little cold blue
steel?
I feel the way I want to feel? There's a
raging fire in my heart tonight?
Tonight? Growing higher and higher
in my soul?
Save me,
I win across the sky?
Take me on your mind?
Take me on your way?
Make you take me out your
mind? With God know?
Take me on your mind? Take me
out my way?